{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The viruses that can achieve neoplastic transformation are called", "opta": "DNA tumor viruses", "optb": "RNA tumor viruses", "optc": "retroviruses HIV", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For gene transfer to be effective, transforming DNA must be", "opta": "incorporated into the bacterial chromosome", "optb": "incorporated into a viral genome", "optc": "free in the bacterial cytoplasm", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Double stranded DNA denaturation with specified limit of temperature is", "opta": "reversible reaction", "optb": "irreversible reaction", "optc": "either (a) or (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "From a single molecule of DNA, PCR can make", "opta": "one additional copy", "optb": "hundreds of copies", "optc": "thousands of copies", "optd": "millions of copies", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Genomic libraries are made from", "opta": "genomic DNA of an organism", "optb": "genomic RNA of an organism", "optc": "genomic cDNA of an organism", "optd": "genomic mRNA of an organism", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bacteriophages are", "opta": "cells in the blood that eat bacteria", "optb": "a class of bacteria", "optc": "bacterial viruses", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Specialized transduction occurs when", "opta": "the bacteriophage incorporates randomly in the bacterial chromosome", "optb": "the bacteriophage never incorporates into the bacterial chromosome", "optc": "the bacteriophage always incorporates at the same position in the bacterial chromosome", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PCR is used", "opta": "to diagnose genetic diseases", "optb": "to solve crimes", "optc": "to study gene function", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "To clone into a plasmid vector, both the plasmid and the foreign DNA are cut", "opta": "with the same restriction enzyme and mixed together", "optb": "with different restriction enzyme and mixed together", "optc": "with the combination of enzymes and then seperated", "optd": "with the combination of enzymes and mixed together", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PCR can be used to amplify a specific fragment of DNA from which of the following?", "opta": "A drop of blood", "optb": "A hair follicle", "optc": "A fragment of skin", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Transformation means", "opta": "formation of a pilus", "optb": "acquiring DNA from the bacterial cell environment", "optc": "plasmid containing a F factor", "optd": "F+ and F- strains of bacteria", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Restriction maps", "opta": "allows comparison between DNA molecules without the need to determine nucleotide sequence", "optb": "allows comparison between DNA molecules but requires to determine nucleotide sequence", "optc": "does not allow comparison between DNA molecules", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is correct?", "opta": "HIV is a retrovirus that kills human helper T cells", "optb": "Causes acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS)", "optc": "Cripples the immunity systems", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A PCR cycle consists of", "opta": "three steps, denaturation, primer annealing and elongation", "optb": "three steps, denaturation, initiation and elongation", "optc": "three steps, primer annealing, elongation and termination", "optd": "three steps, initiation, elongation and termination", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many ds DNA molecule can be produced, which comprise precisely the target region in double strand form during 4th cycle of PCR?", "opta": "Two ds DNA molecule", "optb": "Three ds DNA molecule", "optc": "Eight ds DNA molecule", "optd": "Four ds DNA molecule", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PCR can be used in", "opta": "cloning", "optb": "sequencing", "optc": "medical diagnosis and forensic medicine", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PCR (Polymerase Chain Reaction) can make multiple copies of", "opta": "DNA", "optb": "RNA", "optc": "protein", "optd": "carbohydrate", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PCR is an abbreviation for", "opta": "Protein Change Reaction", "optb": "Polymerase Chain Reaction", "optc": "Positive Charge Reaction:", "optd": "Preliminary Change Rate", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "PCR amplifies millions of copies of", "opta": "a short fragment of DNA", "optb": "the entire genome (all the DNA in a sample)", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "short chain RNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Southern blotting involves", "opta": "electrophoresis of DNA molecules and then blotting the separated DNA bands followed by incubation", "optb": "electrophoresis of DNA molecules and then blotting the separated RNA bands followed by incubation", "optc": "electrophoresis of DNA molecules followed by incubation", "optd": "electrophoresis of RNA molecules and then blotting the separated RNA bands followed by incubation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bactriophages absorb to a bacterial surface and inject the phage DNA through the", "opta": "cell wall into cytosol", "optb": "cell wall into plasmamembrane", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "cell wall into endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a PCR reaction after four cycles, each molecule of a duplex DNA will give rise to", "opta": "16 single strands of DNA", "optb": "16 double stranded DNA", "optc": "18 single strands of DNA", "optd": "18 double stranded DNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Additional mono saccharides are added in Golgi to produce", "opta": "either high mannose type oligosaccharide or a complex type", "optb": "either fructose type monosaccharide or a complex type", "optc": "either high sucrose type polysaccharide or a complex type", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The PCR, polymerase chain reaction is becoming the method of choice for", "opta": "Alteration of gene", "optb": "screening gene", "optc": "sterilization of gene", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Northern blotting is", "opta": "widely different than southern blotting", "optb": "another name for southern blotting", "optc": "analogous to southern blotting", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What technique can be used to determine the murderer who left blood with the victim?", "opta": "DNA sequencing", "optb": "PCR amplification", "optc": "Western blot", "optd": "RFLP mapping", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA fragments in a restriction digest can be separated by electrophoresis in", "opta": "poly acrylamide", "optb": "agarose gel", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}